<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Visual Studio Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio</link>
	<description>The official source of product insight from the Visual Studio Engineering Team</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 02:12:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/10/Microsoft-favicon-cropped31.png</url>
	<title>The Visual Studio Blog</title>
	<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview 3</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/09/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-3/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/09/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-3/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio Previews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=17245</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today we released the third preview of the next update: Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7. The top highlights of this Preview include: Updates to Universal Windows Platform development C++ development improvements Significant updates in Xamarin and .NET Mobile Development Ability to configure installation locations Debugger support for authenticated Source Link Live Unit Testing improvements New... <a aria-label="read more about Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview 3" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/09/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-3/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we released the third preview of the next update: Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7. The top highlights of this Preview include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Updates to Universal Windows Platform development</li>
<li>C++ development improvements</li>
<li>Significant updates in Xamarin and .NET Mobile Development</li>
<li>Ability to configure installation locations</li>
<li>Debugger support for authenticated Source Link</li>
<li>Live Unit Testing improvements</li>
<li>New tooling for migrating to NuGet PackageReference</li>
<li>Connected Service improvements to deployment and Key Vault functionality</li>
</ul>
<p>This preview builds upon the features that debuted in the <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-2/">Preview 2</a> and <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/13/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-1/">Preview 1</a> releases that occurred in March. As always, you can drill into the details of all of these features by exploring the <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/news/releasenotes/vs2017-preview-relnotes">Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview release notes</a>. We appreciate your early adoption, engagement, and feedback as it helps us ship the most high-quality tools to everyone in the Visual Studio community.</p>
<p>We hope that you will install it, use it, and share your feedback with us. To acquire the Preview, you can either <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/preview/">install it fresh from here</a>, you can update the bits directly from the IDE, or if you have an Azure subscription, you can <a href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/marketplace/apps?search=visual%20studio%202017%20latest%20preview&amp;page=1">provision a virtual machine with this latest preview</a>.</p>
<h2>Universal Windows Platform Development</h2>
<p><b>Latest Windows Insider SDK: </b>With Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview 3, the latest Windows Insider Preview SDK (build 17133) is included as an optional component to the Universal Windows Platform development workload. You can choose to install this SDK with Visual Studio to start taking advantage of the latest Windows APIs and features.</p>
<p><b>New Features in Blend for the Updates to the XAML Designer: </b>In the fall of last year, we brought some <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2017/09/11/a-significant-update-to-the-xaml-designer/">drastic changes</a> to the XAML Designer for UWP developers targeting the Windows 10 Fall Creators Update. With these changes, we lost some of the features that our developers have grown to know and love. With Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview 3, we are proud to announce that two big features for Blend are back – Visual State Management tooling, and the Animation tooling with the Objects and Timeline pane! Now, all UWP developers can take advantage of these tools in Blend.</p>
<h2>C++ Development</h2>
<p><b>C++ Standards Conformance</b>: This release includes many conformance improvements, including <a href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2015/p0136r1.html">rewording inheriting constructors</a>, <a href="https://wg21.link/P0127R2">declaring non-type template parameters with auto</a>, <a href="https://wg21.link/p0137r1">std::launder()</a>, and two-phase name lookup. In addition, the MSVC compiler toolset conforms almost fully with the C++17 Standard: when compiling with the /Zc:__cplusplus switch, the value of the __cplusplus macro reflects the correct Standard version numbers.</p>
<p><b>Unit Testing:</b> You can now use <a href="https://aka.ms/codelensUT">CodeLens above each of your unit tests</a> to Run, Debug, and view Test Status.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/UnitTest.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Unit testing" alt="Unit testing" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/UnitTest.png" width="637" height="353" class="" /></a></p>
<p><b>Code Analysis</b><b>: </b>We’ve added the /analyze:ruleset option to cl.exe for filtering down warnings in the C++ Code Analysis tools based on ruleset configuration. This results in a consistent experience between standalone invocations of the compiler and the IDE, and improves performance by running only the rules mentioned in ruleset.</p>
<p><b>Spectre Mitigations in MSVC: </b>The Visual C++ Runtime now supports <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/vcblog/2018/01/15/spectre-mitigations-in-msvc/">mitigations for the Spectre variant 1 vulnerability</a>, and the toolset includes mitigated and non-mitigated versions of the DLLs. We’ve also enabled compiler support for Spectre mitigations in non-optimized builds (/Od).</p>
<p><b>Build Throughput: </b>The /Zf switch is now enabled by default, which enables faster PDB generation when using multiple compilation processes.</p>
<p><b>CMake:</b> The <a href="https://aka.ms/cmaketargetsview">CMake Targets View</a> provides an alternative way to view a CMake project&#8217;s source in the Solution Explorer; instead of a folder-based view, it organizes the code into individual CMake targets.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/CMake.png" rel="noopener"><img width="375" height="455" title="CMake" alt="CMake" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/CMake.png" class="" /></a></p>
<p>In addition, unknown macros that cause tag-parsing errors are now underlined with green squiggles, and source files (.cpp) belonging to CMake projects can now be built individually.</p>
<p><b>IntelliSense: </b>Headers from Linux and Unix-like systems are now automatically downloaded for use by IntelliSense on Windows. These are also used to provide an enhanced IntelliSense experience for Linux native platform development.</p>
<p>For more C++ feature additions, please see the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-preview-relnotes">release notes</a>. <b></b></p>
<h2>Xamarin and .NET Mobile Development</h2>
<p><b>Xamarin.Forms XAML Editing Improvements: </b>Xamarin.Forms developers using Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 will notice a vastly improved IntelliSense experience when editing XAML. The Xamarin.Forms XAML editing experience is now powered by the same engine that powers WPF and UWP. This brings many enhancements to developers, including improved matching, light bulb suggestions, code navigation, error checking, resource completion, and markup extension completion.</p>
<p><b><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/XamarinIntellisense2.gif" rel="noopener"><img width="725" height="362" title="Xamarin Intellisense" alt="Xamarin Intellisense" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/XamarinIntellisense2.gif" class="" /></a></b></p>
<p><b>Modernized project templates: </b>Whether you’re new or a seasoned Xamarin developer, project templates are an important part of the app building journey. We have centralized the cross platform project creation in a single place, modernized <a href="https://blog.xamarin.com/new-xamarin-android-ios-templates/">our iOS and Android native project templates</a> and reduced the time it takes to create a new project.</p>
<p><b>Android Development Improvements:</b> We have made several improvements to the Android development experience. We are now distributing the Android Oreo SDK (Android API level 27) and are shipping the Android emulators with Quick Boot enabled. We have modernized the designer’s property editor. Visual Studio will now detect scenarios where the project requires a different version of the Android SDK that is installed and will download in the background the required components.</p>
<p>Lastly, when you start a compilation, Visual Studio will boot and deploy the Xamarin runtime on your device while the compilation is taking place, thus reducing the time that that you have to wait to see your application show up. With our test application, on a fresh device, with no previous deployment, and including launching the Android emulator, we see the following performance gains:</p>
<p><b><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Android-Emulator-prformance-gains-comparison-table.jpg" rel="noopener"><img width="518" height="247" title="Xamarin Intellisense" alt="Xamarin Intellisense" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Android-Emulator-prformance-gains-comparison-table.jpg" class="" /></a></b></p>
<p><b>Apple Platform Development Improvements:</b> We’ve also made significant improvements to the iOS development experience. The iOS, Mac, tvOS and Watch applications now feature a fully static type system. This brings many benefits, such as smaller applications, faster application startup, and reduced memory usage. We have also introduced the [Weak] attribute for fields that make it simpler to write code that is <a href="https://github.com/xamarin/documentation/blob/c5595b511aebd560e2fc087889fb3dc43bd5c41e/releases/ios/xamarin.ios_11/xamarin.ios_11.10.md#weakattribute">garbage collection friendly</a> in Apple platforms.</p>
<p>Lastly, the provisioning of iOS devices has historically been a chore, requiring multiple trips to the documentation. We have incorporated the same fastlane experience that we shipped on macOS and you can now provision your devices in seconds and keep your entitlements up to date with the click of a button.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Apple-Provision.gif" rel="noopener"><img width="740" height="437" title="Apple Provision" alt="Apple Provision" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Apple-Provision.gif" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>Python</h2>
<p>The new and improved version of the Python debugger is now bundled with the Python extension and on by default, making it easier and faster for you to debug your Python code. For more information, refer to the <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/pythonengineering/2018/03/13/python-in-visual-studio-15-7/">Python debugger blog post</a> that describes this feature.</p>
<h2>NuGet</h2>
<p><b>New tooling for migrating to NuGet PackageReference</b><b>: </b>This release provides out of the box support for <a href="https://aka.ms/nuget-migrator-docs">migrating existing projects based on packages.config to PackageReference</a>. To get started, right-click on the <b>References </b>node in the <b>Solution Explorer</b> and select <b>Migrate packages.config to PackageReference</b>. The tool analyzes the installed NuGet packages, calculates the dependency graph, and categorizes them into top-level and transitive dependencies. It also provides warnings for potential package compatibility issues with PackageReference.</p>
<p><b><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Nuget.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Nuget" alt="Nuget" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Nuget.png" width="493" height="465" class="" /></a></b></p>
<h2>Acquisition</h2>
<p>Starting with Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview 3, you can reduce the installation footprint on your system drive by directing the download cache, shared components, and some SDKs and tools to different locations. Because these pieces are shared among Visual Studio installations, you can only set the locations with your first installation, meaning that you can’t change them later. If you have a solid-state drive (SSD), we recommend that you install the Visual Studio core product on your SSD drive because this will make Visual Studio run significantly faster. For further details on what each of these locations mean, please refer to <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/news/releasenotes/vs2017-preview-relnotes">the preview release notes</a>.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Installation-Locations.jpg" rel="noopener"><img title="Installation Locations" alt="Installation Locations" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Installation-Locations.jpg" width="774" height="330" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>Debugging</h2>
<p><b>Source Link Authentication:</b> The debugger now supports <a href="https://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579-visual-studio-ide/suggestions/19107784-debugger-should-support-authentication-with-source">authenticated Source Link</a> requests for Visual Studio Team Services and private GitHub repositories. When debugging code that was built on another computer, such as a library in a NuGet package, Source Link enables the debugger to show correctly matching source code by downloading it from the internet. To build your own code with Source Link enabled see <a href="https://aka.ms/SourceLinkSpec">https://aka.ms/SourceLinkSpec</a>.</p>
<p>For VSTS repositories, authentication is provided by <a href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dn457348.aspx">signing into Visual Studio</a>. For GitHub, we leverage credentials from the <a href="https://visualstudio.github.com/">GitHub Extension for Visual Studio</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/Git-Credential-Manager-for-Windows#git-credential-manager-for-windows">Git Credential Manager for Windows</a>. If Source Link fails due to an authentication error a new “Source Link Authentication Failed” page is shown to explain the issue. This page allows the user to login to VSTS or GitHub and retry the Source Link request.</p>
<h2>Live Unit Testing</h2>
<p>Live Unit Testing has added support for new project features including embedded pdbs and pdbs specifying <b>/deterministic</b>. Live Unit Testing can also now support projects that use reference assemblies.</p>
<h2>Connected Services</h2>
<p><b>Deployment to Azure App Services on Linux:</b> Visual Studio now offers you the ability to deploy non-containerized applications to Azure App Service on Linux in addition to our previous support for apps built with Docker. To publish your application to App Service and run in Linux, from the Publish dialog choose “App Service Linux” and select “Create new”.  To continue to publish a containerized application to App Service for Containers using Linux, choose “Create new App Service for Containers”.</p>
<p><b>Key Vault Connected Service</b>: Azure Key Vault provides a secure location to safeguard keys and other secrets used by cloud apps.  Securing your project’s secrets is now easier than ever with the ability to create and add a Key Vault to your project as a Connected Service.  Doing so will automatically add configuration, add the required NuGet packages to your project, and enable you to access secrets from the Key Vault in your source code.  Once the Key Vault has been added, you will be able to manage secrets and permissions through the Azure portal.  This is available for both ASP.NET and ASP.NET Core applications.</p>
<h2>Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5 Preview 2</h2>
<p>We’re also releasing a new preview of Visual Studio for Mac, which you can get by switching to the Beta <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mac/update#changing-the-updater-channel">updater channel</a>. This release improves the Razor, JavaScript, and TypeScript web development features we <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-5-preview-1/">announced in our first preview</a>. Additionally, we’re improving project load performance for .NET Core projects and the debugging experience with Unity games. Be sure to check out the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-mac-preview-relnotes">preview release notes</a> for the full list of fixes in this release, driven by your feedback.</p>
<h2>Try out the Preview today!</h2>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Visual Studio Previews, take a moment to read the <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/productinfo/vs2017-release-rhythm">Visual Studio 2017 Release Rhythm</a>. Remember that Visual Studio 2017 Previews can be installed side-by-side with other versions of Visual Studio and other installs of Visual Studio 2017 without adversely affecting either your machine or your productivity. Previews provide an opportunity for you to receive fixes faster and try out upcoming functionality before they become mainstream. Similarly, the Previews enable the Visual Studio engineering team to validate usage, incorporate suggestions, and detect flaws earlier in the development process. We are highly responsive to feedback coming in through the Previews and look forward to hearing from you.</p>
<p>Please get the <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/preview/">Visual Studio Preview</a> today, exercise your favorite workloads, and tell us what you think. If you have an Azure subscription, you can provision <a href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/marketplace/apps?search=visual%20studio%202017%20latest%20preview&amp;page=1">a virtual machine of this preview</a>. You can report issues to us via the <a href="https://aka.ms/vs-rap">Report a Problem</a> tool in Visual Studio or you can share a suggestion on <a href="https://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579">UserVoice</a>. You’ll be able to track your issues in the <a href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Developer Community</a> where you can ask questions and find answers. You can also engage with us and other Visual Studio developers through our <a href="https://gitter.im/Microsoft/VisualStudio">Visual Studio conversation in the Gitter community</a> (requires GitHub account). Thank you for using the Visual Studio Previews.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><img width="200" height="149" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/06/Christine-Ruana-e1498715608219.jpg" /></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><b>Christine Ruana</b> Principal Program Manager, Visual Studio</p>
<p>Christine is on the Visual Studio release engineering team and is responsible for making Visual Studio releases available to our customers around the world.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/09/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Load solutions faster with Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/04/load-solutions-faster-with-visual-studio-2017-version-15-6/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/04/load-solutions-faster-with-visual-studio-2017-version-15-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solution Load]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=17175</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As we have been working to improve the solution load experience in Visual Studio 2017, you may have read our blog about these improvements in version 15.5. With version 15.6, we have introduced parallel project load, which loads large .NET solutions twice as fast as earlier versions when you reload the same solution. This video... <a aria-label="read more about Load solutions faster with Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/04/load-solutions-faster-with-visual-studio-2017-version-15-6/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we have been working to improve the solution load experience in Visual Studio 2017, you may have read our <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2017/11/20/large-c-and-vb-solutions-load-significantly-faster-in-15-5-update/">blog about these improvements in version 15.5</a>. With version 15.6, we have introduced <i>parallel project load</i>, which loads large .NET solutions twice as fast as earlier versions when you reload the same solution. This video compares the time it takes to load a very large solution from the Roslyn repository, with 161 projects, between version 15.5 and 15.6.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Solution-Load-15_5-vs-15_6.mp4" rel="noopener"><img title="solution load performance comparing 15.5 and 15.6" alt="solution load performance comparing 15.5 and 15.6" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Roslyn-solution-showing-solution-load-performance.png" width="834" height="542" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>Parallel project load</h2>
<p>During the first load of a solution, Visual Studio calculates all the IntelliSense data from scratch. In the previous version of Visual Studio 2017, version 15.5, we optimized the calculation of IntelliSense data by parallelizing the design-time build that produces the data. Solutions that were opened for the first time on a machine loaded significantly faster because of this parallelization. IntelliSense data was cached, so subsequent loads of a solution didn’t require a design-time build.</p>
<p>With version 15.6 we wanted to go one step beyond optimizing IntelliSense calculation. We&#8217;ve enabled <i>parallel project load </i>for large solutions that contain C#, VB, .NET Core, and .NET Standard projects. Many Visual Studio customers have machines with at least 4 CPU cores. We wanted to leverage the power of all the CPUs during solution load by loading projects in parallel.</p>
<p>We continuously monitor solution load telemetry coming in through the Customer Experience Improvement Program. We saw that, in aggregate, customers experienced a 25% improvement in solution load times in version 15.6, across all solution sizes. Large .NET solutions experienced even larger improvements, and now load <i>twice as fast</i> as previous versions. A customer with a very large, 400+ project solution told us that their solution now loads 2-4 times faster!</p>
<h2>Solution load is getting leaner</h2>
<p>Parallel solution load is part of the work we’re doing to improve solution load. Another big effort is to get unneeded components out of the way of solution load. Historically, many components and extensions used solution load to perform initialization work, which added to the overall solution load time. We are changing this to make Visual Studio developers productive as quickly as possible. Only critical code that enables navigation, editing, building, and debugging will run during solution load. The rest of the components initialize asynchronously afterwards.</p>
<p>For example, Visual Studio previously scanned git repositories during solution load to light up the source control experience. Not anymore. This process now starts after the solution has loaded, so you can start coding faster.</p>
<p>As another example, Visual Studio used to synchronously initialize the out-of-process C# language service. This code is now optimized to reuse data structures already available in the Visual Studio process. We’re also working with extension owners to delay operations that do not impact the solution load process until after the load has completed.</p>
<p>We have also optimized the Visual Studio solution loader to batch and run all critical solution load operations before any other work can run. Previously, the Visual Studio solution loader fired a subset of solution load events asynchronously. This allowed lower priority work to interfere with solution load. Additionally, there are popular extensions that listen to these events and can block Visual Studio for seconds. This experience confused some customers, because it was not clear when solution load was complete. This logic is now optimized, so that all solution load events fire synchronously during solution load.</p>
<p>While solution load is significantly faster in version 15.6, we are not done yet. You will see us making solution load even leaner in future updates.</p>
<h2>Know what slows you down</h2>
<p>Even with these improvements, it’s still possible for slow blocking operations to get scheduled after the solution has loaded. When this happens, the solution appears loaded, but Visual Studio is unresponsive while it is processing these operations. Visual Studio version 15.6 detects blocking operations and presents a performance tip. This helps extension authors find these issues and gives end users more control over their IDE’s performance.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Performance-tip-in-the-IDE-showing-operations-causing-delays.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Performance tip in the IDE showing operations that cause delays" alt="Performance tip in the IDE showing operations that cause delays" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Performance-tip-in-the-IDE-showing-operations-causing-delays.png" width="765" height="141" class="" /></a></p>
<p>Extension authors can use an asynchronous API that allows extensions to run code without blocking users. We’ve also published <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/extensibility/how-to-diagnose-ui-delays-caused-by-extensions">guidance</a> for extension authors to learn how to diagnose and address responsiveness issues. If you regularly see unresponsiveness notifications for an extension, reach out to the owner of the extension or contact us at <a>vssolutionload@microsoft.com</a>.</p>
<h2>Let us know</h2>
<p>We would love to know how much faster your solution loads in version 15.6. Give it a try and let us know by sending an email to <a>vssolutionload@microsoft.com</a>. You can also tweet about it and include @VisualStudio.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><img width="150" height="410" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/11/Viktor-Veis.png" /></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><strong>Viktor Veis</strong>, Principal Software Engineering Manager, Visual Studio<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/ViktorVeis">@ViktorVeis</a></p>
<p>Viktor runs the Project and Telemetry team in Visual Studio. He is driving engineering effort to optimize solution load performance. He is passionate about building easy-to-use and fast software development tools and data-driven engineering.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/04/04/load-solutions-faster-with-visual-studio-2017-version-15-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/04/Solution-Load-15_5-vs-15_6.mp4" length="3665658" type="video/mp4" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adding support for Debug Adapters to Visual Studio IDE</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/26/adding-support-for-debug-adapters-to-visual-studio-ide/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/26/adding-support-for-debug-adapters-to-visual-studio-ide/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=17135</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since its release, Visual Studio Code&#8217;s extension model, based on well-known web technologies such as TypeScript and JSON, has attracted a great deal of participation from the community, with hundreds of extensions published to provide support for exciting new languages and technologies. Visual Studio 2017 took the first steps towards participating in this ecosystem in... <a aria-label="read more about Adding support for Debug Adapters to Visual Studio IDE" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/26/adding-support-for-debug-adapters-to-visual-studio-ide/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since its release, Visual Studio Code&#8217;s extension model, based on well-known web technologies such as TypeScript and JSON, has attracted a great deal of participation from the community, with hundreds of extensions published to provide support for exciting new languages and technologies. Visual Studio 2017 took the first steps towards participating in this ecosystem in November, with the release of the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/extensibility/adding-an-lsp-extension">Language Server Protocol preview</a>. Now, in Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6, we&#8217;re excited to announce support for another Visual Studio Code extension component &#8211; the <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/extensionAPI/api-debugging">debug adapter</a>. If you&#8217;ve previously written a debugging extension for Visual Studio Code, you can now use it in Visual Studio as well, generally with only minor modifications. If you&#8217;re considering implementing debugging support for a language or runtime, doing so via a debug adapter will allow you to reach both Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code customers without having to support two separate codebases.</p>
<h2>What is a Debug Adapter?</h2>
<p>A debug adapter is a program that can communicate with a debugger UI using the Debug Adapter Protocol. An adapter can act as a bridge between the UI and a separate debugger (such as GDB or LLDB), or can be a debugger in and of itself (such as &#8220;vsdbg&#8221;, which supports CoreCLR debugging on Linux and macOS). The Debug Adapter Protocol is JSON-based, and libraries for working with it are available in many languages, including <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/vscode-debugadapter">Node.JS</a> and <a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Microsoft.VisualStudio.Shared.VsCodeDebugProtocol">C#/VB.Net</a>.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Debug-Adapters-Overview-Diagram.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Debug Adapters Overview Daigram" alt="Debug Adapters Overview Daigram" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Debug-Adapters-Overview-Diagram.png" width="721" height="241" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>How do I get started?</h2>
<p>You will need to have Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6 installed.</p>
<p>Samples and documentation for the Visual Studio Debug Adapter Host are <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/VSDebugAdapterHost">available on GitHub</a>: <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/VSDebugAdapterHost">https://github.com/Microsoft/VSDebugAdapterHost</a>.</p>
<p>On the <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/VSDebugAdapterHost/wiki">Debug Adapter Host wiki</a>, you’ll find walkthroughs that demonstrate testing and packaging a debug adapter for use in Visual Studio. After following the walkthrough, you’ll be able to debug with Visual Studio Code’s “Mock Debug” adapter in Visual Studio:</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Visual-Studio-Code-Mock-Debug-adapter-in-Visual-Studio.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Visual Studio Code Mock Debug adapter in Visual Studio" alt="Visual Studio Code Mock Debug adapter in Visual Studio" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Visual-Studio-Code-Mock-Debug-adapter-in-Visual-Studio.png" /></a></p>
<p>The wiki also contains documentation on new functionality added to the Debug Adapter Protocol to support Visual Studio scenarios, such as the ability to edit values in the &#8220;Watch&#8221; window, control the formatting of data and stack traces, and more.</p>
<p>If your extension also contains a Language Server, you may also be interested in the preview release of Visual Studio’s <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/extensibility/adding-an-lsp-extension">Language Server Protocol support</a>.</p>
<h2>How do I provide feedback?</h2>
<p>You can provide feedback by <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/VSDebugAdapterHost/issues">filing issues on GitHub</a>, or you can email the team directly at <a>vsdahfeed@microsoft.com</a>.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><img width="200" height="149" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Andrew-Crawley.png" /></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><b>Andrew Crawley</b> Sr. Software Engineer, Visual Studio</p>
<p>Andrew is an engineer on the Visual Studio IDE Debugger team, where he works on the Visual Studio Debug Adapter Host.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/26/adding-support-for-debug-adapters-to-visual-studio-ide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2017 Version 15.7 Preview 2</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-2/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio Previews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=17025</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today we released the second preview of the next update: Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7. We hope that you will use this Preview and share your feedback with us. To use the Preview, you can either install it fresh from here, you can update the bits directly from the IDE, or if you have an... <a aria-label="read more about Visual Studio 2017 Version 15.7 Preview 2" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-2/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we released the second preview of the next update: Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7. We hope that you will use this Preview and share your feedback with us. To use the Preview, you can either <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/preview/">install it fresh from here</a>, you can update the bits directly from the IDE, or if you have an Azure subscription, you can <a href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/marketplace/apps?search=visual%20studio%202017%20latest%20preview&amp;page=1">provision a virtual machine with this latest preview (starting tomorrow)</a>.</p>
<p>The top highlights of this Preview include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Improved intellisense for conditional XAML</li>
<li>Additional C++ development improvements</li>
<li>Streamlined configuration for updating UWP apps</li>
<li>Inclusion of TypeScript 2.8</li>
<li>Ability to debug JavaScript files using Microsoft Edge</li>
<li>Tooling to prevent Web application permission problems</li>
<li>Support for building additional project types on the build servers.</li>
</ul>
<p>This second Preview builds upon the <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/13/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-1/">features we added in Preview 1</a>. As always, you can drill into the details of these features by exploring the <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/news/releasenotes/vs2017-preview-relnotes">Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview release notes</a>. We appreciate your early adoption, engagement, and feedback as it helps us ship the most high-quality tools to everyone in the Visual Studio community.</p>
<h2>Productivity</h2>
<p><b>XAML Intellisense</b>: The XAML editor now provides IntelliSense for authoring <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/debug-test-perf/conditional-xaml">conditional XAML</a>. When using a type that is not present in the target min version of your app, the XAML editor now not only warns but also provides several options to fix it. The quick fix figures out the right conditional using statement based on the platform version where the type was first introduced, allowing the app to target a wider range of platform versions while being able to consume the latest controls.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/XAML-IntelliSense.png" rel="noopener"><img title="XAML IntelliSense" alt="XAML IntelliSense" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/XAML-IntelliSense.png" width="1312" height="301" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>C++ Development</h2>
<p><b>Code Analysis</b><b>: </b>Five new rules enforcing items from the <a href="https://github.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines">C++ Core Guidelines</a> regarding use of the <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/GSL">Guidelines Support Library</a><u> are now available</u>.</p>
<p><b>C++ Standards Conformance: </b>Five more C++17 Standard features are added to the compiler and IntelliSense in this release, making MSVC much closer to be fully compliant with the latest C++ Standard. As an example, extend <a href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2016/p0091r3.html">template argument deduction</a> for functions to constructors of template classes – when you construct a class template you no longer have to specify the arguments. You can now have public base classes in aggregate types, so that they can be initialized using aggregate initialization syntax without writing boilerplate constructors. In braced initializer lists, bases are initialized first, followed by data members.</p>
<table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><strong>C++17 Template argument deduction for class </strong></td>
<td valign="top"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top">Before</td>
<td valign="top">After</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top">pair&lt;int, double&gt; p(2, 4.5);</p>
<p>auto t = make_tuple(4, 3, 2.5);</p>
<p>lock_guard&lt;std::mutex&gt; lck(foo.mtx);</td>
<td valign="top">pair p(2, 4.5);</p>
<p>tuple t(4, 3, 2.5);</p>
<p>auto lck = lock_guard(foo.mtx);</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>We are now complete with the full implementation of C++11 <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/vcblog/2016/06/07/expression-sfinae-improvements-in-vs-2015-update-3"><u>Expression SFINAE</u></a>, and have made the corresponding Standard Library changes.<b> </b>We have also implemented parallel algorithms conforming to the ISO C++17 standard.</p>
<p>For more C++ feature additions, please see the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-preview-relnotes">release notes</a>. <b></b></p>
<h2>Universal Windows Platform Development</h2>
<p><b>Automatic updates for sideloaded UWP apps: </b>The Universal Windows Platform allows distributing applications without the Microsoft Store by using a mechanism called “<a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/packaging/appinstaller-root">sideloading</a>”. With Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview 2 using the latest <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windowsinsiderpreviewSDK">Windows 10 Insider Preview SDK</a>, there is now tooling to easily configure the automatic update settings for these UWP apps.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/UWP-Side-load-Update-Settings.png" rel="noopener"><img title="UWP Side load Update Settings" alt="UWP Side load Update Settings" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/UWP-Side-load-Update-Settings.png" width="604" height="517" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>TypeScript and JavaScript Development</h2>
<p><b>Compiler: </b>Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 will include <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/typescript/2018/03/15/announcing-typescript-2-8-rc/">TypeScript 2.8</a>.</p>
<p><b>Developer Productivity: </b>We’ve continued our push to help make TypeScript and JavaScript developers more productive by adding support for fixing all occurrences of a problem in a document (for example, removing unused variables), organizing imports (including sorting and removing unused declarations), and displaying the lightbulb more proactively when optional improvements are possible. We’ve also fixed some of the top issues raised by customers, including premature triggering of snippets, un-cancellable refactorings, hard-to-disable formatting, and incorrect TypeScript version selection. These improvements are powered by TypeScript 2.8, so for the best experience, we recommend updating your existing projects to use the latest TypeScript version.</p>
<p><b>Performance: </b>One of the best ways to make developers more productive is to improve the performance of their tools.  To that end, we’ve made background analysis of closed files optional (<i>Only report diagnostics for files opened in the editor</i> under Tools &gt; Options &gt; TextEditor &gt; JavaScript/TypeScript / Project).  We’ve also added support for jsconfig.json – analogous to tsconfig.json – so that JavaScript developers can fine-tune their language service experience in the same way as TypeScript developers.</p>
<p><b>Debugging using Microsoft Edge</b>: Visual Studio ASP.NET and .NET core developers on Windows Insider builds can now set breakpoints and debug their JavaScript files using Microsoft Edge browser. Visual Studio will use the new <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/devtools-protocol/0.1/">Edge DevTools Protocol</a> developed by the Microsoft Edge team when targeting Microsoft Edge browser, which means that developers will be able to debug and fix JavaScript issues from within Visual Studio in both Microsoft Edge and Google Chrome. We are glad to enable this oft requested feature from our customers and would love to hear what you think about it.</p>
<h2>Web Development</h2>
<p>It is often tricky and time consuming to diagnose runtime application permission problems. In Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7, we’ve made a change to help you identify a specific kind of access issue during development. When running an ASP.NET or ASP.NET Core application on the local machine, the app may not have access to the Key Vault from the account specified under Tools | Options | Azure Service Authentication, and thus won’t be able to run locally. Visual Studio will now detect that case and provide a proactive error during development. This type of diagnostic will shorten the time it takes to discover and fix this local runtime permission problem.</p>
<h2>Build Tools</h2>
<p>The Visual Studio 2017 Build Tools allow you to create build servers without installing the entire Visual Studio editing environment. Over the past few updates, we’ve been expanding the matrix of project types that the Build Tools support. In the last minor release, we added the ability to build TypeScript and Node.js project types, and in this release we are adding support for building additional project types such as Azure, Office and Sharepoint, Mobile development with .NET (Xamarin), ClickOnce, Docker Tools, Test Tools, and installing into containers. <a href="https://aka.ms/vs/15/pre/vs_buildtools.exe">Click here to download</a> the preview release of the Visual Studio Build Tools and try out these new capabilities.</p>
<h2>Try out the Preview today!</h2>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Visual Studio Previews, take a moment to read the <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/productinfo/vs2017-release-rhythm">Visual Studio 2017 Release Rhythm</a>. Remember that Visual Studio 2017 Previews can be installed side-by-side with other versions of Visual Studio and other installs of Visual Studio 2017 without adversely affecting either your machine or your productivity. Previews provide an opportunity for you to receive fixes faster and try out upcoming functionality before they become mainstream. Similarly, the Previews enable the Visual Studio engineering team to validate usage, incorporate suggestions, and detect flaws earlier in the development process. We are highly responsive to feedback coming in through the Previews and look forward to hearing from you.</p>
<p>Please get the <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/preview/">Visual Studio Preview</a> today, exercise your favorite workloads, and tell us what you think. If you have an Azure subscription, you can provision <a href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/marketplace/apps?search=visual%20studio%202017%20latest%20preview&amp;page=1">a virtual machine of this preview</a> (starting tomorrow). You can report issues to us via the <a href="https://aka.ms/vs-rap">Report a Problem</a> tool in Visual Studio or you can share a suggestion on <a href="https://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579">UserVoice</a>. You’ll be able to track your issues in the <a href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Developer Community</a> where you can ask questions and find answers. You can also engage with us and other Visual Studio developers through our <a href="https://gitter.im/Microsoft/VisualStudio">Visual Studio conversation in the Gitter community</a> (requires GitHub account). Thank you for using the Visual Studio Previews.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><img width="200" height="149" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/06/Christine-Ruana-e1498715608219.jpg" /></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><b>Christine Ruana</b> Principal Program Manager, Visual Studio</p>
<p>Christine is on the Visual Studio release engineering team and is responsible for making Visual Studio releases available to our customers around the world.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5 Preview 1</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-5-preview-1/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-5-preview-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 18:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio Previews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=17075</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Earlier this month, we released version 7.4 of Visual Studio for Mac, our IDE for developers on macOS who are building mobile, web, and cloud apps. Today, we’re announcing the first preview of Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5, which you can get by changing the updater channel in Visual Studio for Mac to use... <a aria-label="read more about Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5 Preview 1" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-5-preview-1/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, we released version 7.4 of Visual Studio for Mac, our IDE for developers on macOS who are building mobile, web, and cloud apps. Today, we’re announcing the first preview of Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5, which you can get by changing the updater channel in Visual Studio for Mac to use <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mac/update">the Beta channel</a>. In this release, the top highlights include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Adding new editor support for Razor, JavaScript, and TypeScript.</li>
<li>Improving Azure Functions development with support for the .NET Core Preview SDK and with the introduction of new Azure Functions templates.</li>
<li>Adding support for the latest releases of .NET Core and C#, with .NET Core 2.1 Preview and C# version 7.2.</li>
<li>Making it easier for Xamarin.Forms developers to build apps using .NET Standard.</li>
<li>Continuing to improve IDE performance and stability.</li>
</ul>
<p>See the full <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-mac-preview-relnotes">Visual Studio for Mac 7.5 Preview release notes</a> to learn about all the changes that made it into this release.</p>
<h2>Web Development with Razor, JavaScript, and TypeScript</h2>
<p>Editor support for Razor, JavaScript, and TypeScript have been some of the top web developer requests we have heard. In this release, new editors are being introduced for each of these languages.</p>
<p>With official support for Razor, you now have syntax highlighting and IntelliSense while editing your C# in .cshtml files.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Syntax-Highlighting-and-IntelliSense.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Syntax highlighting and IntelliSense" alt="Syntax highlighting and IntelliSense" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Syntax-Highlighting-and-IntelliSense.png" /></a></p>
<p>In previous releases, our JavaScript editor included support for syntax highlighting and colorization. Now, it’s rewritten to provide smarter colorization, IntelliSense, brace completion, and the rest of the core editor experience. At the same time, support is being added for TypeScript editing; providing the same colorization, IntelliSense, and editor experience as JavaScript.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/TypeScript-editor.gif" rel="noopener"><img title="TypeScript editor" alt="TypeScript editor" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/TypeScript-editor.gif" /></a></p>
<p>Behind the scenes, these three were made possible thanks to a lot of hard work from the Roslyn and Visual Studio JavaScript tooling teams – and Visual Studio for Mac re-uses source code from these editing experiences as they appear in Visual Studio 2017 on PC.</p>
<h2>Build serverless solutions with Azure Functions</h2>
<p>Last year, we introduced preview support for Azure Functions – enabling development of Azure Functions using C# and .NET with full debugger tooling – based on the Mono runtime. Now, a new Functions template dialog is included, along with support for the .NET Core Preview SDK.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Azure-Functions-Templates.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Azure Functions templates" alt="Azure Functions templates" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Azure-Functions-Templates.png" width="644" height="405" class="" /></a></p>
<p>Azure Functions templates enable you to quickly create new functions using the most common triggers and templates. You can access these by creating a new Azure Functions project, right-clicking on your project, and choosing the <b>Add &gt; Add Function…</b> menu.</p>
<h2>.NET Core 2.1 and C# 7.2</h2>
<p>Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5 Preview 1 is the first release supporting the .NET Core 2.1 Preview SDK. You can read all about the .NET Core 2.1 Preview release in the <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dotnet/2018/02/27/announcing-net-core-2-1-preview-1/">announcement blog post</a>. Some of the top improvements: faster build performance, closing gaps in ASP.NET Core and EF Core, better compatibility with .NET Framework, General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and Security compliance. We’ve also added support for <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/dotnet/csharp/whats-new/csharp-7-2">C# 7.2</a>.</p>
<h2>.NET Standard and Xamarin.Forms</h2>
<p>Mobile developers will be happy to see that .NET Standard Library projects are now a fully supported option for sharing code between platforms when building Xamarin.Forms solutions. This release brings numerous bug fixes to improve the .NET Standard developer experience (see the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-mac-preview-relnotes">release notes</a>).</p>
<h2>Improving performance and reliability</h2>
<p>Finally, we continue our push to improve performance and reliability in the IDE. This release focuses on improving IDE startup time, which has decreased by as much as 50% for some users. We’re also fixing top issues and crashes as they come into the Developer Community site – please keep the feedback coming! Some of the top fixes in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/content/problem/166661/vs-2017-community-for-mac-crashes-every-time-on-qu.html">VS 2017 for Mac crashes every time on Quit</a> (first reported by “AI Borns”)</li>
<li><a href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/content/problem/148602/vs-for-mac-crashes-almost-instantly.html">VS for Mac crashes almost instantly</a> (first reported by “Alexander Litvak”)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Feedback</h2>
<p>We can&#8217;t do this alone and we need your help to make the product better! Please try out the Visual Studio for Mac version 7.5 Preview 1 release by <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/mac/">installing Visual Studio for Mac now</a> and <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/mac/update">switching to the Beta update channel in the IDE</a>. Share your comments and bug reports with us on the <a href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/spaces/41/index.html">Developer Community site</a>; you can get there quickly by using the <b>Help &gt; Report Problem…</b> menu from the IDE. We also welcome <a href="http://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/563332-visual-studio-for-mac">feature suggestions</a> on our UserVoice site, which you can also access from the <b>Help &gt; Provide a Suggestion…</b> menu.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/miguel-de-icaza.jpg" rel="noopener"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/miguel-de-icaza-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="250" class="alignnone wp-image-16715" /></a></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><strong>Miguel de Icaza</strong>, Distinguished Engineer, Mobile Developer Tools</p>
<p>Miguel is a Distinguished Engineer at Microsoft, focused on the mobile platform and creating delightful developer tools. With Nat Friedman, he co-founded both Xamarin in 2011 and Ximian in 1999. Before that, Miguel co-founded the GNOME project in 1997 and has directed the Mono project since its creation in 2001, including multiple Mono releases at Novell. Miguel has received the Free Software Foundation 1999 Free Software Award, the MIT Technology Review Innovator of the Year Award in 1999, and was named one of Time Magazine’s 100 innovators for the new century in September 2000.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/21/visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-5-preview-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Supporting JUnit 5 in Visual Studio Code</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/19/supporting-junit-5-in-visual-studio-code/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/19/supporting-junit-5-in-visual-studio-code/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 16:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio Code]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=16995</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After supporting the widely adopted JUnit 4 with the Java Test Runner extension for Visual Studio Code, we’ve received suggestions to add additional test frameworks, like JUnit 5 and TestNG. We’ve added initial support for JUnit 5, including running, debugging test cases as well as test report. Please give us a try and let us... <a aria-label="read more about Supporting JUnit 5 in Visual Studio Code" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/19/supporting-junit-5-in-visual-studio-code/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After supporting the widely adopted JUnit 4 with the <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-test">Java Test Runner</a> extension for Visual Studio Code, we’ve received suggestions to add additional test frameworks, like JUnit 5 and TestNG. We’ve added initial support for JUnit 5, including running, debugging test cases as well as test report. Please give us a try and let us know your feedback.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.19.Supporting-JUnit-5-in-Visual-Studio-Code.JUnit5_.gif" rel="noopener"><img title="JUnit 5 in Visual Studio Code" alt="JUnit 5 in Visual Studio Code" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.19.Supporting-JUnit-5-in-Visual-Studio-Code.JUnit5_.gif" /></a></p>
<h2>Expression Evaluation based Conditional Break Point</h2>
<p>After introducing expression evaluation in our <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/01/08/visual-studio-code-java-debugger-adding-step-filter-and-expression-evaluation/">January release</a> for the Java <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-debug">debugger</a> extension, we are bringing the functionality to conditional break points. Now, you can set your breakpoint to break when an expression evaluates to true. We believe this could be a very useful feature when debugging your Java application using Visual Studio Code.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.19.Supporting-JUnit-5-in-Visual-Studio-Code.ConditionalBP.gif" rel="noopener"><img title="Conditional Break Point" alt="Conditional Break Point" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.19.Supporting-JUnit-5-in-Visual-Studio-Code.ConditionalBP.gif" width="662" height="403" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>Other Updates</h2>
<p>We&#8217;ve also added new features to our Java on Visual Studio Code extension lineup, including:</p>
<h3><a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-test">Java Test Runner</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Trigger tests from test explorer on different levels</li>
<li>Add command to open log file</li>
<li>Add setting to specify the position of test report</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=adashen.vscode-tomcat">Tomcat</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Add several context commands in Tomcat Explorer</li>
<li>Add support for JVM customization and Tomcat server configuration</li>
<li>Add command palette entries for user input</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-maven">Maven</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Add support for auto-update maven project explorer when pom.xml is updated</li>
</ul>
<h2>Try it out</h2>
<p>Please don’t hesitate to try Visual Studio Code for your Java development, and let us know your thoughts! Install the <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-debug">Java Extension Pack</a> which includes <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=redhat.java">Language Support for Java by Red Hat</a>, <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-debug">Debugger for Java</a>, <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-maven">Maven</a>, and the <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-java-test">Java Test Runner</a>.</p>
<h2>Additional resources</h2>
<ul>
<li>If you’re working on Spring Boot, there are also extensions for <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=Pivotal.vscode-spring-boot">Spring Boot Tools</a> and <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=vscjava.vscode-spring-initializr">Spring Initializr</a> we’ve developed in partnership with Pivotal.</li>
<li>Learn more about <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/languages/java">Java on Visual Studio Code</a>.</li>
<li>Explore our step by step <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/java/java-tutorial">Java Tutorials on Visual Studio Code</a>.</li>
</ul>
<table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" width="600" border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="150"><img width="180" height="410" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/10/Xiaokai-He.jpg" /></td>
<td valign="top" width="450"><strong>Xiaokai He</strong>, Program Manager<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/XiaokaiHe">@XiaokaiHe</a></p>
<p>Xiaokai is a program manager working on Java tools and services. He’s currently focusing on making Visual Studio Code great for Java developers, as well as supporting Java in various of Azure services.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/19/supporting-junit-5-in-visual-studio-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio at GDC 2018</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/14/visual-studio-at-gdc-2018/</link>
		<comments>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/14/visual-studio-at-gdc-2018/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=16955</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Next week, the world’s largest professional game industry event kicks off in San Francisco: Game Developers Conference (GDC) 2018. We’re incredibly excited to engage with all developers at the event looking to join the growing community of more than half a million monthly active developers building great games with Visual Studio today. Microsoft experts will... <a aria-label="read more about Visual Studio at GDC 2018" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/14/visual-studio-at-gdc-2018/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Next week, the world’s largest professional game industry event kicks off in San Francisco: Game Developers Conference (GDC) 2018. We’re incredibly excited to engage with all developers at the event looking to join the growing community of more than half a million monthly active developers building great games with Visual Studio today. Microsoft experts will be at the event and are looking forward to have great conversations with you. Here’s an overview of where you can find us.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/GDC-2018.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Visual Studio at GDC 2018" alt="Visual Studio at GDC 2018" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/GDC-2018.png" /></a></p>
<h2>Expo booth and theater sessions</h2>
<p>Visual Studio experts will be present in the main Microsoft booth in the South Tower Lobby, together with experts from Azure, Mixer, PlayFab, Windows, and others. Come talk to us about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Using <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/?os=win">Visual Studio 2017</a>, <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/?os=macos">Visual Studio for Mac</a>, and <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Code</a> to build games for all platforms across desktop, mobile, and console with a variety of game engines.</li>
<li>How <a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/team-services/">Visual Studio Team Services</a> can help you share code, plan, build, and ship games with unlimited private Git repositories, cloud-hosted build agents, Agile planning tools and Kanban boards and much more.</li>
<li>Leveraging <a href="http://visualstudio.com/app-center">Visual Studio App Center</a> to automate testing your games on real Android and iOS devices, distribute to testers and app stores, and monitoring real-world usage.</li>
</ul>
<p>Located just outside the South Hall entrance, you will find experts to talk to about all these topics, as well as amazing experiences from Microsoft to participate in. You will also be able to join 20-minute theater sessions here, covering a wide range of hot topics.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Location.png" rel="noopener"><img title="Where we will be" alt="Where we will be" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/Location.png" width="459" height="357" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>DevOps breakout session</h2>
<p>On March 22, Microsoft’s Cloud Developer Advocates Jessica Deen (<a href="https://twitter.com/jldeen">@jldeen</a>) and Abel Wang (<a href="https://twitter.com/AbelSquidHead">@AbelSquidHead</a>) will deliver a breakout session on <a href="http://schedule.gdconf.com/session/devops-for-game-developers-with-microsoft-azure-presented-by-microsoft-azure/856646">DevOps for Game Developers with Team Services and Microsoft Azure</a> at 11:30 AM.</p>
<h2>So much more…</h2>
<p>Of course, this is just the tip of the iceberg. There’s great session content from various Microsoft teams, access to experts across Xbox, Azure, and PlayFab, and much more to help you build great games with the help of our technology.</p>
<p>To learn more about all the different ways you can interact with Microsoft at GDC 2018, take a look at our <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/gdc-2018/">Microsoft @ GDC page</a>. There you will also find a <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/files/gdc-2018-agenda.pdf">PDF version of this information</a>, so you can keep it with you on paper or your phone for easy reference.</p>
<p>We hope to see you at the event and look forward to talking with you all! And if you can&#8217;t make it to the event, be sure to follow <a href="https://twitter.com/visualstudio">@VisualStudio</a> for the latest from GDC 2018 and beyond.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/rajen-kishna.jpg"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/rajen-kishna.jpg" alt="" width="329" height="329" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16675" /></a></td>
<td><strong>Rajen Kishna</strong>, Sr. Product Marketing Manager<br />
<a target="_blank" href="http://www.twitter.com/rajen_k" rel="noopener">@rajen_k</a></p>
<p>Rajen does product marketing at Microsoft for Visual Studio for Mac, as well as mobile and game developer tools. He has a background in application development for various platforms and a passion for technology all-up.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/14/visual-studio-at-gdc-2018/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2017 Version 15.7 Preview 1</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/13/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 18:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio Previews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=16805</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week we released Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6 and Visual Studio for Mac version 7.4, and today we are releasing the first preview of the next minor update: Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7.   We hope that you will use this Preview and share your feedback with us.  To install, you can get it fresh... <a aria-label="read more about Visual Studio 2017 Version 15.7 Preview 1" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/13/visual-studio-2017-version-15-7-preview-1/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week we released Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6 and Visual Studio for Mac version 7.4, and today we are releasing the first preview of the next minor update: Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7.   We hope that you will use this Preview and share your feedback with us.  To install, you can <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/preview/" rel="noopener">get it fresh from here</a> or, if you already have a prior Preview installed, you can either click on the in-product notification or <a href="#acquisition">check for an update directly</a>.  Alternatively, if you have an Azure subscription, you can <a target="_blank" href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/marketplace/apps?search=visual%20studio%202017%20latest%20preview&amp;page=1" rel="noopener">provision a virtual machine with this latest preview</a> (starting tomorrow).</p>
<p>The top highlights of this Preview are described below and include productivity enhancements, better diagnostics, additional C++ development improvements, better management of Android and iOS environments, updated tooling for Universal Windows Platform and .NET Core projects, and an improved update experience.  Please note that this is the first set of version 15.7 features; more goodness awaits in the next Preview. And as always, you can view the complete list of new features and details on how to enable them in the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/news/releasenotes/vs2017-preview-relnotes" rel="noopener">Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 Preview release notes</a>.</p>
<p>We appreciate your early adoption and feedback as it helps us ship the most high-quality tools to everyone in the Visual Studio community. Thank you for engaging in Visual Studio previews!</p>
<h2>Productivity</h2>
<p><strong>UI Responsiveness</strong>: Performance and productivity are two areas we continually work on improving in Visual Studio.  In Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7, we’re making some of the debugging windows asynchronous, which means that they will no longer block Visual Studio as they do work.  This change will allow for faster stepping because you can continue interacting with Visual Studio without interruption. In this Preview, you should see the first of these improvements in the Threads, Callstack and Parallel Stacks windows, with more window improvements in future releases. As always, we’d love to hear your feedback on the Visual Studio debugger: email <a target="_blank" href="mailto:vsdbgfb@microsoft.com" rel="noopener">vsdbgfb@microsoft.com</a>.</p>
<h2>Diagnostics</h2>
<p><strong>Snapshot Debugging:</strong> The Visual Studio <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/debugger/debug-live-azure-applications" rel="noopener">Snapshot Debugger</a> can now be launched from the<em> Debug -&gt; Attach Snapshot Debugger </em>menu item. The snapshot debugger in Visual Studio enables you to diagnose and debug issues your Azure Web Applications without impacting the availability of the application. You can learn more about the Visual Studio Snapshot debugger through our <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/debugger/debug-live-azure-applications" rel="noopener">docs</a>.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.08.15.7Prev1.SnapshotDebugMenu-gif.gif" rel="noopener"><img width="332" height="250" title="Snapshot Debug Menu" alt="Snapshot Debug Menu" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.08.15.7Prev1.SnapshotDebugMenu-gif.gif" class="" /></a></p>
<p><strong>IntelliTrace Events and Snapshots for .NET Core: </strong>IntelliTrace&#8217;s new <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/debugger/how-to-use-intellitrace-step-back" rel="noopener">step-back debugging feature</a>, first shipped in Visual Studio 2017 version 15.5, is now supported for debugging .NET Core applications. The feature automatically takes a snapshot of your application on each breakpoint and debugger step, enabling you to go back to a previous breakpoint or step and view the state of the application as it was in the past. To enable this feature, go to Tools &gt; Options &gt; IntelliTrace settings &gt; and select ‘IntelliTrace events and snapshots’. IntelliTrace step-back is a Visual Studio Enterprise feature available on Windows 10 Anniversary Update or above for debugging .NET applications.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/10/Step-Back-Forward-Buttons.gif" rel="noopener"><img title="Step Back Forward Buttons" alt="Step Back Forward Buttons" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2017/10/Step-Back-Forward-Buttons.gif" /></a></p>
<h2>C++ Development</h2>
<p><strong>Code Analysis:</strong> C++ Core Check is now part of the default toolset for native code analysis. Whenever code analysis is executed over a project, a subset of rules is enabled from C++ Core Check in addition to default recommended rules.</p>
<p><strong>Linux project properties: </strong>We added parallel compilation support for Linux projects, which may significantly improve build times; this can be enabled via Property Pages &gt; C/C++ &gt; Max Number of Parallel Compilation Jobs.  We also added the &#8220;Public Project Include Directories&#8221; Linux project property to improve consumption of includes from project-to-project references in Linux solutions.</p>
<p><strong>Compiler throughput: </strong>We’ve made changes in <a target="_blank" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/vcblog/2016/10/05/faster-c-build-cycle-in-vs-15-with-debugfastlink/" rel="noopener">fastlink</a> PDBs to reduce in-heap memory consumption by 30%. These changes reduce the time to hit the first breakpoint when debugging and makes single-stepping significantly faster. These changes also eliminate a major cause of out-of-memory crashes when debugging large projects.</p>
<p><strong>ClangFormat:</strong> <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/clangformat" rel="noopener">ClangFormat support</a> for C++ developers was added to the IDE. Like with EditorConfig, you can use ClangFormat to automatically style and format your code as you type, in a way that can be enforced across your development team.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.08.15.7Prev1.ClangFormat1.png" rel="noopener"><img width="876" height="417" title="Clang Format" alt="Clang Format" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.08.15.7Prev1.ClangFormat1.png" class="" /></a></p>
<h2>Universal Windows Platform Development</h2>
<p>We have included the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windowsinsiderpreviewSDK" rel="noopener">Windows 10 Insider Preview SDK</a>, Build 17110 as an optional component associated with the Universal Windows Platform workload. We have also added support for generating <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/machine-learning/overview#automatic-interface-code-generation" rel="noopener">Windows Machine Learning</a> class wrappers for an ONNX file that is added to a UWP project. Currently, both components are optional but will be included by default in future preview releases.</p>
<h2>.NET Mobile Development</h2>
<p>Figuring out what Android SDKs to install for mobile development can be time consuming. Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7 adds a new Android SDK manager that takes the guesswork out of managing Android SDK installations. When opening a project for which you don’t have SDKs installed to build it, a notice will appear to help you download the required SDKs. After hitting “Download &amp; Install” and accepting the relevant license agreement, the correct SDKs will automatically be installed in the background for you.</p>
<p>We are also making provisioning iOS devices for development easier. In Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7, we’re replacing requesting a development certificate, generating a signing key, adding a device in the Developer Center, and creating a provisioning profile with a single button. All the heavy lifting of provisioning an iOS device is handled for you in less than 30 seconds.</p>
<h2>ASP.Net and Web Development</h2>
<p>Visual Studio 2017 version 15.7, currently in preview, is the recommended version of Visual Studio to use with <a target="_blank" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dotnet/2018/02/27/announcing-net-core-2-1-preview-1/" rel="noopener">.NET Core 2.1, which is also currently in preview</a>. .NET Core 2.1 has a bunch of new features like a new managed socket implementation and various improvements like better support for HTTPS.  It doesn’t matter which you install first, either way Visual Studio 15.7 will find .NET Core 2.1 and offer it as an option.</p>
<div id="acquisition">
<a name="acquisition"></a><br />
<h2>Acquisition</h2>
</div>
<p>The update experience is now more streamlined than ever in Visual Studio 2017. The yellow notification flag in the upper right-hand corner of the IDE will still notify you when an update is available, but you can now also initiate your own update check by going to Help -&gt; Check for Updates. After you save your work and choose &#8220;Update Now&#8221;, Visual Studio will automatically apply the update and then reopen back where you left.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.08.15.7Prev1.Acquisition1.jpg" rel="noopener"><img width="469" height="345" title="Acquisition" alt="Acquisition" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/2018.03.08.15.7Prev1.Acquisition1.jpg" class="" /></a></p>
<p>This new update experience is just the beginning of our investments in this area, and we&#8217;d love to hear your feedback in this space, particularly about how and when you want to apply updates. Please share your ideas with us via the <a target="_blank" href="https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=869274" rel="noopener">Update Survey</a><span>.</span></p>
<h2>Try out the Preview today!</h2>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Visual Studio Previews, take a moment to read the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/productinfo/vs2017-release-rhythm" rel="noopener">Visual Studio 2017 Release Rhythm</a>. Remember that Visual Studio 2017 Previews can be installed side-by-side with other versions of Visual Studio and other installs of Visual Studio 2017 without adversely affecting either your machine or your productivity.  Previews provide an opportunity for you to receive fixes faster and try out upcoming functionality before they become mainstream. Similarly, the Previews enable the Visual Studio engineering team to validate usage, incorporate suggestions, and detect flaws earlier in the development process. We are highly responsive to feedback coming in through the Previews and look forward to hearing from you.</p>
<p>Please get the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/preview/" rel="noopener">Visual Studio Preview</a> today, exercise your favorite workloads, and tell us what you think.  If you have an Azure subscription, you can provision <a target="_blank" href="https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/marketplace/apps?search=visual%20studio%202017%20latest%20preview&amp;page=1" rel="noopener">a virtual machine of this preview</a> (starting tomorrow).  You can report issues to us via the <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/vs-rap" rel="noopener">Report a Problem</a> tool in Visual Studio or you can share a suggestion on <a target="_blank" href="https://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579" rel="noopener">UserVoice</a>. You’ll be able to track your issues in the <a target="_blank" href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/" rel="noopener">Visual Studio Developer Community</a> where you can ask questions and find answers. You can also engage with us and other Visual Studio developers through our <a target="_blank" href="https://gitter.im/Microsoft/VisualStudio" rel="noopener">Visual Studio conversation in the Gitter community</a> (requires GitHub account).</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><img width="200" height="149" src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/christine-ruana.jpg" /></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><b>Christine Ruana</b> Principal Program Manager, Visual Studio</p>
<p>Christine is on the Visual Studio release engineering team and is responsible for making Visual Studio releases available to our customers around the world.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6, Visual Studio for Mac version 7.4 Released</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/06/visual-studio-2017-version-15-6-visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-4-released/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 18:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Debugging and Diagnostics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[V]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2017]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio for Mac]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=16745</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, we released updates to both Visual Studio 2017 and Visual Studio for Mac. These updates include major performance improvements, fixes and new features to help you be more productive.... <a aria-label="read more about Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6, Visual Studio for Mac version 7.4 Released" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/03/06/visual-studio-2017-version-15-6-visual-studio-for-mac-version-7-4-released/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, we released updates to both Visual Studio 2017 and Visual Studio for Mac. Start your download now while you browse the rest of this post: download <a target="_blank" href="http://aka.ms/vs-download?utm_source=vsblog&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=15.6rtw" rel="noopener">Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6</a> or <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/vs4mac-download?utm_source=vsblog&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=15.6rtw" rel="noopener">Visual Studio for Mac</a>. We’ll trigger the update notification flag in the tools in the coming days.</p>
<h2>Visual Studio 2017 version 15.6</h2>
<p>I’ll highlight some of the major changes in this post, but to see the complete list of changes and features, please see our <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-relnotes" rel="noopener">Release Notes</a>.</p>
<h3>Performance</h3>
<p>We have kept working to improve many aspects of performance and with this update, three things stand out:</p>
<ul>
<li>This update makes solution load for managed code in particular much faster. Users of .NET Core will experience an average of 20% faster load times, with a more noticeable improvement for solutions with 30+ projects.</li>
<li>The Debugger’s Threads window is even faster with this release. Now you can interact with Visual Studio while it processes data in the background, which is useful when you&#8217;re debugging multithreaded applications.</li>
<li>Many VS customers run extensions, which can impact performance. To help you troubleshoot performance issues, this update adds notifications for extensions that may be causing UI delays. This notification lets you directly disable the extension to improve performance or turn off future notifications.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic12.png"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic12.png" alt="" width="1094" height="122" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16755" /></a></p>
<h3>Unit Testing</h3>
<p>Improvements to .NET Unit Testing include <a target="_blank" href="https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=862824" rel="noopener">real time test discovery</a> and we added the hierarchy view to improve the navigation experience in the Test Explorer.</p>
<p><a href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic21.png"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic21-500x303.png" alt="" width="500" height="303" class="alignnone wp-image-16765 size-mediumlarge" /></a></p>
<p>The real time test discovery feature finds any C# and Visual Basic tests, even if you haven&#8217;t built your managed project. This feature uses Roslyn to update the <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/test/test-explorer-faq#4-tests-now-appear-in-test-explorer-while-i-type-without-having-to-build-my-project-what-changed" rel="noopener">Test Explorer</a> in just seconds as you add, remove, or edit tests. We also added options to <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/test/test-explorer-faq#3-assembly-based-discovery-is-no-longer-working-for-my-project-how-do-i-turn-it-back-on" rel="noopener">configure test discovery</a>.</p>
<p>Improvements to unit testing for C++ include <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/boostdynamic" rel="noopener">Boost.Test item templates</a> and the added support for the Boost dynamic library. Also, Visual Studio<a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/fjmazk" rel="noopener"> automatically discovers your tests</a> in CMake projects (CTest, Google Test, and Boost.Test). After you build, you&#8217;ll receive an even more granular view of your tests:</p>
<p><a href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic3.png"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic3.png" alt="" width="345" height="433" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16775" /></a></p>
<h3>C++</h3>
<p>As part of our ongoing effort towards <strong>C++ 17 Standards Conformance</strong>, the C++ workload now includes support for stable_sort, partition, inline vector::emplace_back in parallel, and &lt;memory_resource&gt; as well as <a target="_blank" href="http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2016/p0135r1.html" rel="noopener">guaranteed copy elision</a> so you don&#8217;t have to construct artificial copy or move constructor for types where copy elision will happen.</p>
<p>To make it easier to catch errors beyond your active configuration, <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/weym4n" rel="noopener">IntelliSense errors for inactive configurations</a> now appear as purple squiggles in the editor. You can set the number of configurations you want to process in Tools &gt; Options &gt; Text Editor &gt; C/C++ &gt; Advanced.</p>
<p><a href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic4.png"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/03/pic4.png" alt="" width="403" height="124" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16785" /></a></p>
<p>We also made C++ improvements for <a target="_blank" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/vcblog/2018/02/23/arithmetic-overflow-checks-in-c-core-check/" rel="noopener">arithmetic overflow checks in C++ Core Check</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/codeanalysis156" rel="noopener">single file code analysis</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/vcblog/2018/01/04/visual-studio-2017-throughput-improvements-and-advice/" rel="noopener">throughput performance and advice</a>. You can discover more features for increasing your productivity on our <a target="_blank" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/vcblog/" rel="noopener">Visual C++ Team Blog</a>.</p>
<h3>.NET Mobile Development</h3>
<p>This release adds a feature to configure your macOS build environment automatically, to make building iOS apps with Visual Studio on Windows easier. Visual Studio will handle the heavy lifting of setup, removing the need to install and update your Mac build machine manually.</p>
<p>We also added the ability for both Windows and Mac users to deploy iOS apps over the network with Wi-Fi debugging. To get started, simply <a target="_blank" href="https://help.apple.com/xcode/mac/9.0/index.html?localePath=en.lproj#/devbc48d1bad" rel="noopener">pair a wireless device with Xcode</a>, and use it as your deployment target.</p>
<h3>Build Tools</h3>
<p>The <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/downloads/#build-tools-for-visual-studio-2017" rel="noopener">15.6 Build Tools</a> lets you build servers without a full Visual Studio installation. Build Tools now supports TypeScript and Node.js project types in addition to support for C++, ASP.NET, and .NET Core for Desktop projects. Other improvements to the MSBuild component of the Build Tools include the ability to easily and seamlessly leverage NuGet to resolve SDKs without extra package modification. We’ve created a <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/Microsoft/MSBuildSdks" rel="noopener">SDK repository</a> for the community to use. More information is available <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/msbuild/how-to-use-project-sdk" rel="noopener">here</a>, and please provide <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/Microsoft/msbuild/issues" rel="noopener">MSBuild feedback here</a>.</p>
<h2>Visual Studio for Mac version 7.4</h2>
<p>Visual Studio for Mac version 7.4 is also available today. It includes improvements in performance and stability, as well as fixes for many of the top reported issues. This release includes support for macOS High Sierra and C# 7.1, and core architectural changes for C# editing (powered by Roslyn), resulting in improved IntelliSense performance and typing responsiveness.</p>
<p>You can read the complete <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/releasenotes/vs2017-mac-relnotes" rel="noopener">release notes</a> and access <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/visual-studio-mac/" rel="noopener">Visual Studio for Mac downloads</a> on VisualStudio.com.</p>
<h2>Share Your Feedback</h2>
<p>As always, we want to know what you think. Please install <a target="_blank" href="http://aka.ms/vs-download?utm_source=vsblog&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=15.6rtw" rel="noopener">Visual Studio 2017 Version 15.6</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/vs4mac-download?utm_source=vsblog&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=15.6rtw" rel="noopener">Visual Studio for Mac</a> and share your thoughts and concerns.</p>
<p>Please let us know any issues you have via the <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/vs-rap" rel="noopener">Report a Problem</a> tool in Visual Studio. You can track your issues in the <a target="_blank" href="https://developercommunity.visualstudio.com/" rel="noopener">Visual Studio Developer Community</a> where you can ask questions and find answers. You can also engage with us and other Visual Studio developers through our new <a target="_blank" href="https://gitter.im/Microsoft/VisualStudio" rel="noopener">Gitter community</a> (requires GitHub account), make a product suggestion through <a target="_blank" href="https://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/121579-visual-studio-ide" rel="noopener">UserVoice</a>, or get free installation help through our <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/support/" rel="noopener">Live Chat support</a>.</p>
<table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2" width="600" border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" width="150"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2016/03/JohnMontgomery1_2013-small.jpg" width="165" height="201" /></td>
<td valign="top" width="450"><strong>John Montgomery</strong>, Director of Program Management for Visual Studio<br />
<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Johnmont" rel="noopener">@JohnMont</a></p>
<p>John is responsible for product design and customer success for all of Visual Studio, C++, C#, VB, JavaScript, and .NET. John has been at Microsoft for 17 years, working in developer technologies the whole time.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join me on March 2, 2018 for a Developer Tools AMA</title>
		<link>https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/02/26/join-me-on-march-2-2018-for-a-developer-tools-ama/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 20:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visual Studio Blog]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Visual Studio]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/?p=16685</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A lot has happened since I last hosted a Reddit “Ask Me Anything” (AMA) nearly two years ago. Our team launched Visual Studio for Mac in late 2016 and released it the following May. Shortly thereafter, we introduced live coding of mobile apps with .NET code with our Live Player. We made it easy to embed... <a aria-label="read more about Join me on March 2, 2018 for a Developer Tools AMA" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/2018/02/26/join-me-on-march-2-2018-for-a-developer-tools-ama/" class="read-more">Read more</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lot has happened since I last hosted a Reddit “Ask Me Anything” (AMA) nearly two years ago.</p>
<p>Our team launched <a target="_blank" href="https://www.visualstudio.com/vs/visual-studio-mac/" rel="noopener">Visual Studio for Mac</a> in late 2016 and released it the following May. Shortly thereafter, we introduced live coding of mobile apps with .NET code with our <a target="_blank" href="https://www.xamarin.com/live" rel="noopener">Live Player</a>. We made it easy to embed .NET into native applications with <a target="_blank" href="https://developer.xamarin.com/guides/cross-platform/dotnet-embedding/" rel="noopener">.NET Embedding</a> and we have been working with Unity to deliver a great experience to their users. We completed Mono ports to the PlayStation 4 and Xbox One, made great progress in unifying Mono and .NET Core, shipped a <a target="_blank" href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/webdev/2018/02/06/blazor-experimental-project/" rel="noopener">prototype to run .NET in WebAssembly</a> and brought CSS and Flex layout to Xamarin.Forms.</p>
<p><strong><i>Note: the following short link will be updated once the Reddit AMA post is live.</i></strong><br />
Please join me in our <a target="_blank" href="https://aka.ms/miguelama" rel="noopener"><strong>Ask Me Anything</strong></a><strong> with Miguel de Icaza on March 2, 12 – 2 PM Pacific Time. </strong></p>
<div title="Add to Calendar" class="addeventatc">Add to Calendar<br />
<span class="start">03/02/2018 12:00 PM</span><br />
<span class="end">03/02/2018 2:00 PM</span><br />
<span class="timezone">America/Los_Angeles</span><br />
<span class="title">Ask Me Anything with Miguel de Icaza</span><br />
<span class="description">Please join the Reddit Ask Me Anything (AMA) with Miguel de Icaza on making .NET developers more successful with Microsoft developer tools: https://aka.ms/miguelama</span><br />
<span class="location">https://aka.ms/miguelama</span></div>
<div style="line-height: 22px"><br></div>
<p>I look forward to answering the questions on what we have done, how we have done it and what we think about the future of mobile development in a Reddit AMA this Friday.</p>
<table width="600" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="150" valign="top"><a target="_blank" href="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/miguel-de-icaza.jpg" rel="noopener"><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2018/02/miguel-de-icaza-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="250" class="alignnone wp-image-16715" /></a></td>
<td width="450" valign="top"><strong>Miguel de Icaza</strong>, Distinguished Engineer, Mobile Developer Tools</p>
<p>Miguel is a Distinguished Engineer at Microsoft, focused on the mobile platform and creating delightful developer tools. With Nat Friedman, he co-founded both Xamarin in 2011 and Ximian in 1999. Before that, Miguel co-founded the GNOME project in 1997 and has directed the Mono project since its creation in 2001, including multiple Mono releases at Novell. Miguel has received the Free Software Foundation 1999 Free Software Award, the MIT Technology Review Innovator of the Year Award in 1999, and was named one of Time Magazine’s 100 innovators for the new century in September 2000.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
